Joel Ferguson

Address: 11 Falcon Heights

BT23 4GF

Mobile: 07711986297

Email – joel081112@icloud.com

Profile

FdEng graduate in Software Engineering with 8 months experience. Experienced Sales Assistant with a demonstrated history of working in the retail industry. Skilled in Java, C#, SQL, Databases and Microsoft Excel. Currently focused on BEng Software Engineering at Ulster University.

Education

Student from 09/2018 at Ulster University Jordanstown with entry into Year 2 studying for BEng Software Engineering.

- Successful completion of Foundation Degree with an overall mark of 60% in level 5 modules, and minimum 55% in all taught level 5 modules got me into year 2 of the course.
- Current modules include Programming 2 and 3, Data Communication and Networks, Database Engineering and Systems Development.

Graduated 06/2018 from Belfast MET with S1 Distinction FdEng Software Engineering accredited by Ulster University.

- In second year modules I attained 77% in programming 3, 59% in web programming 2, 75% in Maths for software engineers and 84% in work based learning.
- · While in my first year I attained the MTA Database Fundamentals Certificate 2017.
- First year modules included web programming 1, java programming 1 and 2 and databases 1 and 2 averaging 70%.
- An assignment was a group project which my team went to the NI Best Awards.. It was a java application that took the idea of making it an easier experience for customers to go to the cinema with which achieved a mark of 87% overall.

I attended Regent House from 2008 to 2015 attaining

- 4 A-Levels, with Maths-B, Further Maths-D, Physics-D and Economics-C earning my Maths in 08/2014 and 2015.
 the rest 08/
- 10 GCSE's, with Maths-A*, English language-B earning my Maths in 08/2012 and the rest 08/2013.

IT Skills Profile

- Applications NetBeans, Access, SQL server, Visual Studio, GitLab, Phpmyadmin, StarUML, AutoCAD, Balsamiq.
- Development Languages Java, C#, SQL CSS, TSQL, ASP.net

Other Skills

- In playing football and cricket, since I was 5 years old, I have learnt the value of teamwork.
- Being a Boys Brigade leader and taking the boys for drill I have developed my communication and leadership skills to get the boys to look somewhat in formation.
- Assignments has developed my time management. Timeframes were made to ensure assignments was not overdue.

Work Experience

· 02/2018-present Fortress SEFA

Software Engineer Intern

Jobs that included Microsoft Excel, Access Databases, SQL and AutoCAD with excel integration to speed up production process and make the production process traceable. Through formulas, importing and exporting of data I was able to make interfaces that would be helpful to the company, along with constant communication and team work being imperative for the required outcome to be successful.

· 08/2014-present Tesco Springhill

General Assistant

My responsibilities since joining have spanned over many departments. Through working the shop floor, I have needed to be hard working to get a job done before a certain deadline and making sure the department I am in looks its best. Through working checkouts, I have developed my communication skills and become more confident in talking to people I don't know.

I got the award of employee of the month for 09/2015 for "getting some wow comments and always being happy and cheerful".

10/2013-01/2014 Ards Evangelical bookshop

Volunteer

This was to enable me to develop my skills and part of the queens badge I was working towards. I also had to show communication skills, being punctual, work as a team and keep the shop tidy.

Interests and Achievements

Sports

I have been part of a sports team all my life with it being both football and cricket. Currently being part of the Ards Cricket Club.

BB leadership

Learning to be a good Boys Brigade leader was what I wanted to do and I started that off by completing the Presidents badge and developing for a few months with boys aged 8-11 and taking them for games, to where I am now and taking the company section for drill every week.

Marathon

Being a team player and a part of a sport that was high intensity running and short distances I decided to challenge myself and run a marathon. I started training in January 2016 and ran a time of 3 hours 29 mins in May 2016 in the Belfast marathon.

References

- Paddy Mooney (tutor)
 Fdn Software Engineering Belfast Met <u>pmooney@belfastmet.ac.uk</u>
- Rudy Van Merkom Fortress Sefa 07955339119